So a brother in the comments asked me,
how can we bring softness into a relationship?
Contrary to the triggered men in my comments,
I believe softness is not about feminine or masculine.
It's about how you show up.
Softness is the difference between showing up amenable
and showing up oppositional.
Now amenable is a word that can get a bad rap
at a certain point because what it means in the beginning
is someone who is willing to be responsive,
willing to listen, willing to compromise.
But it can go too far past that
to where people expect that person to be submissive.
So that's when people feel like
that's softness, that's weakness.
But then there's oppositional.
And oppositional is confrontational for no reason
other than simply to defend.
And often in our partnerships,
both parties are showing up way more oppositional
and not enough amenable.
The softness comes in everybody creating a space
where we can all be amenable
because we don't feel like we gotta be oppositional
because we didn't come here to fight.
We came here to love.
Ba-dum-bum.
For more on this, check out my Small Doses podcast episode,
Side Effects of Softness.